Mindfulness has been shown to have a number of meaningful health benefits—it can help reduce anxiety and promote healing in those suffering from chronic illness.
正念已被证明对健康有不少切实的益处——它能帮助慢性病患者减轻焦虑、促进康复。
The practice is based on an insight first described in ancient Buddhist texts that human beings have the capacity to observe experience without being caught up in it.
这种修习基于一个最早见于古代佛教典籍的见解：人有能力对体验加以观察，而不陷入其中。
This means simply that it is possible to observe ourselves having a craving, or a happy thought, or even a scary emotion, without reacting in the moment in a way that amplifies the feeling or sends the mind spiraling off into thinking about old memories or anticipating events.
这不过是说，我们能够观察到自己产生了某种渴望、某个快乐的念头，甚至某种可怕的情绪，而不在当下做出反应，进而放大这种感受，或让思绪一发不可收拾地陷入对往事的回想或对未来之事的预想。
This practice of mindfulness can help calm the mind and the body as we learn not to react to experience with likes and dislikes or judgments of good and bad.
随着我们学会不以好恶或好坏评判来对体验做出反应，这种正念修习能帮助身心平静下来。
It does not make us cold or indifferent but more fully present.
正念修习并不会让我们变得冷漠或无动于衷，而是让我们更全然地专注于当下。
One of the challenges of practicing mindfulness in our contemporary world is that there has been a profound transformation in human attention.
在当今世界修习正念的挑战之一在于，人类的注意力已经发生了深刻的转变。
The artist Jenny Odell argues that in our “attention economy” human attention has been transformed into a commodity that big corporations buy and sell.
艺术家珍妮·奥德尔认为，在我们所处的“注意力经济”中，人类的注意力已经变成了大公司买卖的商品。
This economy rests on a technological revolution of mobile phones and social media that makes it possible for corporations to target our attention with their content at every moment.
这种经济建立在手机和社交媒体这场技术革命之上，这场革命让公司能够时时刻刻用自己的内容锁定我们的注意力。
The devices most people use are a perpetual diversion from the present moment.
大多数人使用的设备无休无止地把人的注意力从当下引开。
The result is that it can feel as though our ability to focus, and be fully present, has been stolen.
结果就是，我们可能会觉得，自己集中注意力、全然专注于当下的能力仿佛被偷走了。
But mindfulness can help us resist the attention economy and relish the things that make life special, like being together with those we love.
但正念可以帮助我们抵御注意力经济，细细品味那些让生活变得特别的事物，比如和所爱之人在一起。
Most mindfulness research focuses on the individual benefits of the practice, but some scholars assert that we can not only practice mindfulness for ourselves but also practice it for others.
大多数正念研究关注的是这种修习给个人带来的益处，但一些学者断言，我们不仅可以为自己修习正念，也可以为他人修习正念。
It can help us build stronger, healthier relationships.
正念能帮助我们建立更牢固、更健康的人际关系。
The sad truth is that living in the attention economy, most of us have become bad listeners.
可悲的事实是，生活在注意力经济之中，我们大多数人都已成了不善于倾听的人。
However, just as it is possible to watch ourselves having an experience without reacting, it’s possible to watch another person have an experience without getting tied up in reactivity and judgment.
然而，正如我们能够观察自己经历某种体验而不做出反应，我们也能够观察另一个人经历某种体验，而不陷入下意识的反应和评判之中。
The gift of mindfulness is a practice of listening with compassion to others describe their experiences.
正念这份礼物是这样一种修习：怀着慈悲心倾听他人讲述自己的经历。
To give this gift means putting away your phone, turning off social media, and setting aside other common distractions.
送出这份礼物，意味着收起手机、关掉社交媒体，并抛开其他常见的干扰。
It means practicing being fully present in another person’s presence and listening to them with complete attention without judgment, while resisting the urge to make the interaction about you.
这意味着练习在他人面前全然专注于当下，全神贯注、不加评判地倾听对方，同时克制住让互动围着自己转的冲动。
If we judge the value of gifts based on their price, this gift may seem worthless, but in a distracted world, it is a precious one.
如果我们根据价格来衡量礼物的价值，这份礼物也许显得一文不值；但在这个注意力涣散的世界里，它却是一份珍贵的礼物。